Gould family papers
Litchfield Historical Society
Gould family papers
1799-1923
Litchfield Historical Society 7 South Street, P.O. Box 385 Litchfield, CT, 6759 URL: http://www.litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org/archon Email: archivist@litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org Phone: 860-567-4501 Fax: 860-567-3565
Gould, John Warren Dubois, 1881-1924; Gould, Edward Sherman, 1837-1905; Gould, Mary Elizabeth (Dubois) Potter
0.42
Small collection of correspondence between members of several generations of the Gould and Dubois families. Includes some genealogical notes.
1931-08-0
Biographical Note
John Warren Dubois Gould was the son of Edward Sherman Gould (1837-1905) and Arabella (Ludlow) Gould. He graduated from New York Universtiy as a civil engineer and spent some of his career working on irrigation projects in the West. In 1910 he married Louisa Fisk. Later he became a specialist in reorganizing bankrupt companies. He was the great-grandson of James Gould (1770-1838) of Litchfield, Conn.
Scope and Contents
Small collection of correspondence between members of several generations of the Gould and Dubois families. Includes some genealogical notes.
Arrangement of Materials
The collection is arranged in 2 series:
1. Correspondence
2. Miscellaneous
Related Materials
Litchfield Law School Collection, Litchfield Historical Society.
Information about related materials is available at http://www.litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Family Name:
Gould family
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Appraisal Information
These papers relate to the descendants of James Gould (1770-1838) who assisted Tapping Reeve with the Litchfield Law School and later ran the Law School in Litchfield, Connecticut.
Other Information
This collection was processed with support from the Council on Library and Information Resources (CLIR).
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Correspondence
  - Dubois, George W, 1895 Apr 18 (Folder 1)
    Letter to his nephew E. Sherman Gould with family news & plans for the summer.
  - Dubois, George W., 1871 Jul 27 (Folder 2)
    Letter to his sister Mary E. (Dubois) Gould with information about genealogical research being done by another Dubois.
  - Gardiner, Asa Bird, 1896 Feb 26 (Folder 3)
    Letter to E. Sherman Gould (1837-1905) about genealogy involving Uriah Tracy and the Gould family.
  - Gould, Edward Sherman (1805-1885), 1872 Jul (Folder 4)
    Receipt from Yale College for a portrait of his father Judge James Gould.
  - Gould, Edward Sherman(1805-1885), 1865 Jun 27 (Folder 5)
    Document from Paris, France identifying E. Sherman Gould as a bearer of dispatches from the legation to the United States.
  - Gould, Edward Sherman(1837-1905), 1895-1898 (Folder 6)
    - Gould, Edward Sherman(1837-1905), 1893 May 6 (Folder 6)
      Document from U.S. Dept. of State requesting that E. Sherman Gould be given safe passage.
    - Gould, Edward Sherman (1837-1905), 1895 Sep 9 (Folder 6)
      Document from U.S. Dept. of State idenfifying E. Sherman Gould and requesting that he be given safe passage.
    - Gould, Edward Sherman (1837-1905), 1898 Oct 26 (Folder 6)
      Document signed by the governor of Havana giving E. Sherman Gould safe passage to the United States.
  - Gould, Edward Sherman(1837-1905) & Gould, Arabella (Ludlow), 1902-1903 (Folder 7)
    7 letters to their son John Warren Dubois Gould with family news including the 1903 Apr 16 letter reporting the death of John's brother Edward Ludlow Gould. Engineering details for bridges, dams, etc.
  - Gould, James, 1807 Jul 10 (Folder 8)
    Letter to Roger M. Sherman requesting information about the case of Messrs North & Wadhams in Danbury. News of Mr. Tracy's illness is alarming - he may not recover.
  - Gould, James, 1834 Jul 3 (Folder 9)
    Letter to his son Edward Sherman Gould (1805-1885) giving advice about the route to take home for a visit.
  - Gould, James Reeve, 1828 May 24 (Folder 10)
    Letter to his brother Edward Sherman Gould (1805-1885) concerning business matters.
  - Gould, John, 1897-1903 (Folder 11)
    11 letters to Edward Sherman Gould (1837-1905) from John Gould in Hatherleigh, Devon, England with some Gould, comments on life, politics and events in England and the U.S., including the Boer War. Letter of 1903 May 6 sends condolences on the death of E.S. Gould's son.
  - Gould, John Warren Dubois, 1914-1923 (Folder 12)
    Letter, copies of letters, and notes concerning the gift of pierces of one of the original timbers of the Gould Law School given by John Warren Dubois Gould, great grandson of James Gould, to various people & museums including the Poconnuck Historic Society, his cousin Charles W. Gould, James Newton Gunn, Judge E.A. Armstrong, William E. Curtis, and Julius M. Mayer.
  - Gould, Julia & Gould, Sally (Tracy), Mrs. James, 1839 Jan 31 (Folder 13)
    Letter to Edward Sherman Gould (1805-1885) from his sister and mother with family news, need of money, and receipt of a book.
  - Gould, Mary E. (Dubois) Potter, Mrs. Edward, 1831-1832 (Folder 14)
    - Gould, Mary E. (Dubois) Potter, Mrs. Edward, 1831 Nov 27 (Folder 14)
      Letter from Mary E. Potter [before she married Edward S. Gould] dated from Paris, France to her parents Cornelius and Sarah P. with description of life in Paris and events in France.
    - Gould, Mary E. (Dubois) Potter, Mrs. Edward, 1831 Dec 8 (Folder 14)
      Letter from Mary E. Potter [before she married Edward S. Gould] from Paris, France to her sister Sarah in New York with description of life in Paris, including the houses, fashions, and countryside.
    - Gould, Mary E. (Dubois) Potter, Mrs. Edward, 1832 Jan 30 (Folder 14)
      Letter from Mary E. Potter [before she married Edward S. Gould] from Paris, France to her father Cornelius Dubois in New York with news that she is leaving for Italy. She had sent gifts for the family on the ship Charlemagne but it was almost wrecked in a storm and had to return to England. Request for some funds. She had visit with Gen. LaFayette
  - Gould, Mary E. (Dubois), Mrs. Edward S., 1865 Oct 2 (Folder 15)
    Letter from Heidelberg, Germany to her son Edward Sherman Gould (1837-1905) with news of their journey, children, and activities.
  - Gould, Robert Howe, 1848-1851 (Folder 16)
    2 letters written from London to his sister-in-law Mary E. (Dubois) Gould, Mrs. Edward S. Gould with information about Goulds in England. He remarks on the game of whist and is sending her some whist counters.
  - Mackay, Alex, 1865 Jul (Folder 17)
    Letter written from New York to Edward Sherman Gould with reminiscences of past July 4th celebrations, discussion of politics,etc.
  - Robertson, J.A., 1905 Jan 25 (Folder 18)
    Typed letter written from Monteroy, Mexico to Cornelius Dubois, in response to a telegram from C. Dubois informing him of the death of his cousin E. Sherman Gould.
  - Tracy, Lauri, 1896 Mar 16 (Folder 19)
    Letter written from New Haven to Mr. Gould concerning the descendants of Uriah Tracy and the Gould family.
- Miscellaneous
  - Gould, 1819 (Folder 1)
    Notebook of poems and extracts copied from various books. Possibly by Edward Sherman Gould (1805-1885) when he attended the Litchfield Female Academy.
  - List VI, undated (Folder 2)
    Handwritten list of student literary assignments mostly about plays.
  - Ludlow, Daniel, 1799 (Folder 3)
    Two descriptions of Insurance on ships issued by Daniel Ludlow. One is dated 6 Feb 1799 for the Ship Cleopatra with Capt. Henry Rogers from New York to La Gugra that was captured by French privateers and carried into Curacoa. The second is dated 21 Jan 1799 for Brig Molly with Captain Peter Kelly sailing from Philadelphia to Balboa, Spain and was captured by a French privateer.
  - Play manuscript, Undated (Folder 4)
    An undated and unsigned hand written manuscript for a play.